<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Colebrooke Parish Devon</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/tags/police/</link><description>Latest blog posts from Colebrooke Parish Devon</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 10:20:43 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colebrooke.org/tags/police/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Colebrooke Bellringers Bell Ringing Marathon</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/colebrooke-bellringers-bell-ringing-marathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 16:40:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/colebrooke-bellringers-bell-ringing-marathon/</guid><description>On 9th March 1991 at 5.00 pm six bellringers and two peal callers gathered at St. Andrews Church Colebrooke to ring a peal of call changes on Colebrooke’s enormous and tricky 18cwt peal of bells that consisted of 1507 call changes where different pairs of bells exchange places in a sequence of six.
The occasion was to raise money for the refurbishment of Colebrooke’s bells. Much needed refreshments were laid on by volunteers at the village hall afterwards.</description></item><item><title>Gregorys of Colebrooke</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/gregorys-of-colebrooke/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 12:50:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/gregorys-of-colebrooke/</guid><description>The Gregorys of Colebrooke (and beyond) Brownsland/Broomsland Home of The Gregorys in 1860
Brownsland Colebrooke was formerly a farm of about 70 acres lying below what is now Sheppark Farm. The name Sheppark referred to the field Sheep Park which used to stretch from Brownsland farmhouse down to the railway line with other smaller fields, no longer in existence, surrounding the farmstead. (Early records referred to the farm as Brownsland but from the Colebrooke estate sale of 1919 it became known as Broomsland.</description></item><item><title>The Bell Inn Colebrooke</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-bell-inn-colebrooke/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:59:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-bell-inn-colebrooke/</guid><description>The Bell Inn Colebrooke Readers may be surprised to learn that the dwelling now known as The Old Bell Inn was an inn for a relatively short period. The original public house of that name was situated in what is now the NW corner of the churchyard. According to 17th and early 18th century, churchwardens accounts it was then known as The Church House and appeared to be in constant need of repair.</description></item><item><title>Cob Buildings</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/cob-buildings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:56:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/cob-buildings/</guid><description>Cob Building Cicely Fox Smith
OLD cob wall
Have falled at last;
Us knawed he might
A good while past.
Great-grandad he
Built thicky wall
With maiden earth
And oaten straw.
He built en in
The good old way,
And there he’ve stood
Until to-day.
But wind and rain
And frost and snaw
Have all combined
To lay en law.</description></item><item><title>Coleford Police Station</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/coleford-police-station/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 10:20:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/coleford-police-station/</guid><description>Coleford Police Station Before being moved to Copplestone during the 1920s, Coleford had its constable for over 60 years.
Initially, when the Devon Constabulary underwent a significant overhaul in 1856, a guideline was introduced whereby a constable would be provided to look after an area based on acreage and population. This resulted in most parishes gaining the services of a constable. Jesse Snell, a shoemaker from Kilmington, was Colebrooke’s first PC and c1860 was living at Colebrooke with his family.</description></item><item><title>The Great Flood of Coleford 1841</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-great-flood-of-coleford-1841/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:50:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-great-flood-of-coleford-1841/</guid><description>The Great Flood of Coleford 1841 In November 1841 the bottom of Coleford was devastated by floods.
After a vestry meeting chaired by Mr Robert Madge of Copplestone House, the following appeal appeared in the Western Times.
Severe Loss in The Great Storm In consequence of the great fall of rain which occurred on Monday the 29th of November great damage was done in the village of Coleford. The water rose to such a height as to overwhelm workshops, stables, cellars, and a great part of some dwelling houses, some of which were levelled to the ground.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Church Bells History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-bells-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-bells-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Church Bells History There have been bells ringing at Colebrooke for centuries, in common with many Devon churches. Even a parish church as small as Colebrooke has supported, almost continuously, the numerous small expenses and occasionally large ones involved in keeping a ring of bells in working order. A large number of records survive which demonstrate to us the dedication with which, among all their other duties, our forbears took care of the bells which we still ring today.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Church History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Church History Introduction. Just under 50 years ago in the constant pursuit of fundraising for the upkeep of the Church, a little booklet was published priced 1/6d (71/2p) entitled “The History of the Church and Parish of St. Andrews, Colebrooke”. This excellent little book was researched and written by Rev. Vyvyan Hope M.A. F.S.A. Rev. Hope who at that time had recently retired from Radley College, was secretary of Friends of Exeter Cathedral and Cathedral Receiver.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Parish Hall History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-hall-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-hall-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Parish Hall History Miss Mary Pope with members of the Parish Council and Village Hall Committee
Photograph of the official opening of the Village Hall in 1960 by Miss Mary Pope with members of the Parish Council and Village Hall Committee Left to Right: Miss Mary Pope, Mrs. F. Lowndes, Mr. A.C. Thorne, Mrs. L. Olding, Mr. E. J. Mock, Mr. E. H. Pennington, Mr. F. W.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Parish History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Parish History Colebrooke Parish THE MANOR Bishop BARTHOLOMEW, in his letter to King Henry II, c. 1170, claimed that “the town of Colebrooke has always from the beginning been, and still is, a part of the Manor of Crediton which belongs to the Church of Exeter and the Episcopal See”. Thus when the Domesday Survey was made in 1086, the manor lands were included in the Crediton totals without being named.</description></item><item><title>Coleford’s Pronunciation</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colefords-pronunciation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colefords-pronunciation/</guid><description>Coleford’s Pronunciation Coleford in Devon can be pronounced wrongly by a great number of people. The long-standing locals and the correct way to pronounce Coleford is Coal ford, with the O and R in the Ford part as “or”
The Correct Way: We, the residents of Coleford hear all sorts of alternative expressions used for our village name:
Culfud, Colefud &amp; Colefurd being the most common examples of how to annoy the locals.</description></item></channel></rss>