<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Colebrooke Parish Devon</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/tags/ve-day/</link><description>Latest blog posts from Colebrooke Parish Devon</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 15:07:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colebrooke.org/tags/ve-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paschoe House Occupants 1870 - 1940</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/paschoe-house-occupants-1870-1940/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:55:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/paschoe-house-occupants-1870-1940/</guid><description>Some Interesting Occupants of Paschoe House 1870 - 1940 After the Calmady-Hamlyn family ceased to live in the new house at Paschoe, it was occupied by various tenants until St Georges School arrived in 1940.
An early occupier was Mr Robert Lodwick Esq. He was a sporting gentleman who, within a few weeks of his arrival, had invited the local hunt to breakfast at Paschoe. He was also something of an entertainer and, at local events, would delight the audience with humorous songs.</description></item><item><title>Paschoe House</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/paschoe-house/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:44:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/paschoe-house/</guid><description>Paschoe House In 1613 Daniel Hamlyn married Joan Tuckfield and settled at Paschoe, thus beginning an association with Colebrooke, which was to last over 300 years. In the early 18th century, their importance was such that a faculty was granted to enable the Coplestone Chantry in the church to be known as the Paschoe Aisle. This is why the Hamlyn memorials feature on the north wall. (A faculty in the 1960s saw it become the Coplestone Aisle again.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke War Memorials</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/colebrooke-war-memorials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:33:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/colebrooke-war-memorials/</guid><description>1914 -1918 In Colebrooke church, on the north wall of the north aisle are two memorials to the service provided by the men of Colebrooke in The Great War. A brass memorial on a marble base contains the names of the fourteen men of the parish who gave their lives in this conflict. One of the more poignant names is Frederick Erscott of Coombe Lodge, only son of George Erscott gardener to Mrs Sinclair Smith of Coombe House.</description></item><item><title>V E Day in Coleford 1945</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/v-e-day-in-coleford-1945/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 15:07:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/v-e-day-in-coleford-1945/</guid><description>V E DAY 1945 Memories of an eight-year old of V E Day in Coleford by Neville Enderson On Tuesday, May 8th, after Victory in Europe was declared early in the morning, Colebrooke Sports Committee, sadly no longer in existence, swiftly organised a day of sports and a tea for the children. No doubt, with hostilities gradually coming to an end, there had been meetings before this to make arrangements for the big day when it arrived.</description></item><item><title>Spencer Cottage</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/spencer-cottage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 11:54:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2022/03/spencer-cottage/</guid><description>Painting of Spencer Cottage - Post office
SPENCERS COLEFORD Most people are familiar with various guide books and estate agents telling us how Charles 1st either reviewed his troops, stabled his horse or even slept in the porch at Spencers in 1644. Charles indeed passed through Coleford on July 29th 1644, having spent the previous night at Crediton and was at Bow by the night of the 29th.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Water</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2021/12/colebrooke-water/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 15:58:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2021/12/colebrooke-water/</guid><description>I grew up listening to greybeards of the area opining that the name Colebrooke originally meant “Land of the Cool Brooks”, which Colebrooke parish has many. With that in mind, it may come as a surprise for people to learn that the village of Colebrooke suffered badly from lack of water until the 1950s. My memories of this stem from the war years and just after, as a schoolboy watching people carrying water in buckets from the Vicarage Well, a source of water which was then in the vicarage garden but now in the grounds of The Oyster… The carrying apparatus consisted of a square frame into which a yoke had been fitted with a bucket holding just over 2 gallons (c 10 litres) on either side.</description></item><item><title>Gateway To Penstone - Penstone Bridge</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2021/08/gateway-to-penstone-penstone-bridge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 09:20:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2021/08/gateway-to-penstone-penstone-bridge/</guid><description>THE GATEWAY TO PENSTONE The memories of a Victorian structure as told to me by the late Penstone Bridge ​ I was erected some 170 years ago together with my “twin”, Waterleat Bridge, a couple of hundred yards south, who for unknown reasons has recently been labelled Yeoford Bridge. In reference books, it is Waterleat Bridge No 573, 183 miles from Waterloo. We were built to enable the railway, which had recently been extended from Bristol to Exeter, to carry its passengers and goods through to Barnstaple.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Revel</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/12/colebrooke-revel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 16:02:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/12/colebrooke-revel/</guid><description>COLEBROOKE REVEL About 200 years ago the people of Colebrooke would be getting ready for their annual festivities. However, The Colebrooke Revel seems to have been taking place long before this and originally began with a church service on the morning of the Sunday nearest the 7th of July followed by a day of sporting activities.
In 1896 a paper read to the Devonshire Association regarding the revels of Devon over the previous 100 years mentioned Colebrooke and said it had become noteworthy for its “Revel Buns”</description></item><item><title>The Great Fire of Colebrooke</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/11/the-great-fire-of-colebrooke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 10:09:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/11/the-great-fire-of-colebrooke/</guid><description>The Great Fire of Colebrooke At the western side of the churchyard, by the road leading up to the village hall, three rows of graves cover the area once occupied by a row of thatch cottages. On the afternoon of 24th August 1893 these cottages, including the grocer’s shop, were destroyed in one of the most massive conflagrations in Colebrooke. The alarm was raised by the schoolmaster Mr John Sharland who from his house beside the school (Chenery House) could see smoke rising at the back of one of the cottages occupied by retired farmer Mr John Cooper.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Bellringers Bell Ringing Marathon</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/colebrooke-bellringers-bell-ringing-marathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 16:40:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/colebrooke-bellringers-bell-ringing-marathon/</guid><description>On 9th March 1991 at 5.00 pm six bellringers and two peal callers gathered at St. Andrews Church Colebrooke to ring a peal of call changes on Colebrooke’s enormous and tricky 18cwt peal of bells that consisted of 1507 call changes where different pairs of bells exchange places in a sequence of six.
The occasion was to raise money for the refurbishment of Colebrooke’s bells. Much needed refreshments were laid on by volunteers at the village hall afterwards.</description></item><item><title>Gregorys of Colebrooke</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/gregorys-of-colebrooke/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 12:50:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/gregorys-of-colebrooke/</guid><description>The Gregorys of Colebrooke (and beyond) Brownsland/Broomsland Home of The Gregorys in 1860
Brownsland Colebrooke was formerly a farm of about 70 acres lying below what is now Sheppark Farm. The name Sheppark referred to the field Sheep Park which used to stretch from Brownsland farmhouse down to the railway line with other smaller fields, no longer in existence, surrounding the farmstead. (Early records referred to the farm as Brownsland but from the Colebrooke estate sale of 1919 it became known as Broomsland.</description></item><item><title>The Bell Inn Colebrooke</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-bell-inn-colebrooke/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:59:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-bell-inn-colebrooke/</guid><description>The Bell Inn Colebrooke Readers may be surprised to learn that the dwelling now known as The Old Bell Inn was an inn for a relatively short period. The original public house of that name was situated in what is now the NW corner of the churchyard. According to 17th and early 18th century, churchwardens accounts it was then known as The Church House and appeared to be in constant need of repair.</description></item><item><title>Cob Buildings</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/cob-buildings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:56:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/cob-buildings/</guid><description>Cob Building Cicely Fox Smith
OLD cob wall
Have falled at last;
Us knawed he might
A good while past.
Great-grandad he
Built thicky wall
With maiden earth
And oaten straw.
He built en in
The good old way,
And there he’ve stood
Until to-day.
But wind and rain
And frost and snaw
Have all combined
To lay en law.</description></item><item><title>Coleford Police Station</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/coleford-police-station/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 10:20:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/coleford-police-station/</guid><description>Coleford Police Station Before being moved to Copplestone during the 1920s, Coleford had its constable for over 60 years.
Initially, when the Devon Constabulary underwent a significant overhaul in 1856, a guideline was introduced whereby a constable would be provided to look after an area based on acreage and population. This resulted in most parishes gaining the services of a constable. Jesse Snell, a shoemaker from Kilmington, was Colebrooke’s first PC and c1860 was living at Colebrooke with his family.</description></item><item><title>The Great Flood of Coleford 1841</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-great-flood-of-coleford-1841/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:50:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/10/the-great-flood-of-coleford-1841/</guid><description>The Great Flood of Coleford 1841 In November 1841 the bottom of Coleford was devastated by floods.
After a vestry meeting chaired by Mr Robert Madge of Copplestone House, the following appeal appeared in the Western Times.
Severe Loss in The Great Storm In consequence of the great fall of rain which occurred on Monday the 29th of November great damage was done in the village of Coleford. The water rose to such a height as to overwhelm workshops, stables, cellars, and a great part of some dwelling houses, some of which were levelled to the ground.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Church Bells History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-bells-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-bells-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Church Bells History There have been bells ringing at Colebrooke for centuries, in common with many Devon churches. Even a parish church as small as Colebrooke has supported, almost continuously, the numerous small expenses and occasionally large ones involved in keeping a ring of bells in working order. A large number of records survive which demonstrate to us the dedication with which, among all their other duties, our forbears took care of the bells which we still ring today.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Church History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-church-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Church History Introduction. Just under 50 years ago in the constant pursuit of fundraising for the upkeep of the Church, a little booklet was published priced 1/6d (71/2p) entitled “The History of the Church and Parish of St. Andrews, Colebrooke”. This excellent little book was researched and written by Rev. Vyvyan Hope M.A. F.S.A. Rev. Hope who at that time had recently retired from Radley College, was secretary of Friends of Exeter Cathedral and Cathedral Receiver.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Parish Hall History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-hall-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-hall-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Parish Hall History Miss Mary Pope with members of the Parish Council and Village Hall Committee
Photograph of the official opening of the Village Hall in 1960 by Miss Mary Pope with members of the Parish Council and Village Hall Committee Left to Right: Miss Mary Pope, Mrs. F. Lowndes, Mr. A.C. Thorne, Mrs. L. Olding, Mr. E. J. Mock, Mr. E. H. Pennington, Mr. F. W.</description></item><item><title>Colebrooke Parish History</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colebrooke-parish-history/</guid><description>Colebrooke Parish History Colebrooke Parish THE MANOR Bishop BARTHOLOMEW, in his letter to King Henry II, c. 1170, claimed that “the town of Colebrooke has always from the beginning been, and still is, a part of the Manor of Crediton which belongs to the Church of Exeter and the Episcopal See”. Thus when the Domesday Survey was made in 1086, the manor lands were included in the Crediton totals without being named.</description></item><item><title>Coleford’s Pronunciation</title><link>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colefords-pronunciation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:09:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.colebrooke.org/blog/2020/06/colefords-pronunciation/</guid><description>Coleford’s Pronunciation Coleford in Devon can be pronounced wrongly by a great number of people. The long-standing locals and the correct way to pronounce Coleford is Coal ford, with the O and R in the Ford part as “or”
The Correct Way: We, the residents of Coleford hear all sorts of alternative expressions used for our village name:
Culfud, Colefud &amp; Colefurd being the most common examples of how to annoy the locals.</description></item></channel></rss>